Are you sold on the idea that voter turnout does not matter for elections in American politics? What do you find appealing or troubling about that idea? How might turnout matter, despite the research findings you’ve seen in this lesson? (stereotypically) 

I am not sold on the idea that voter turnout does not matter for elections in American politics. While it seemingly does not affect election results, I still believe that voter turnout is imperative to molding the nation for the future. There are several things I find troubling about the voter turnout statistics sprinkled throughout the readings. First of all, the fact that there is a low voter turnout for the younger, qualified voters is appalling. The youth must take politics more seriously and vote to mold the country's politics for the future. With only older voters, there will be an imbalance and a slowing of forward thinking in election results. In addition, the low turnout of racial minorities is troubling, yet not surprising to me. I have to say that I have  biases being an African American woman who identifies as a liberal Democrat. Stereotypically and generally, I believe that minorities lean towards the Democratic party because of the more progressive thinking. In my understanding of the political parties, Democrats are often seen as the more liberal group. For women, voting Democrat is appealing because of the progressive thinking of reproductive rights. (Apparently reproductive rights qualify as "progressive thinking.") For the working class, the Democratic party stresses a equal education and closing the wage gap. For African Americans and other people of color, Democrats show more diversity and therefore are more appealing to vote for. Shared experiences offer a unique connection and reason to vote. A high voter turnout is necessary to continue progress in this country.